Matthew Enyina

Full stack engineer with 3+ years of experience developing web services. My most vital skills are Node.js and React.js. I'm very flexible in working with different technologies and methodologies, so I can quickly learn and adapt to new environments.

Ketu, Lagos State.
+2348061313069
enyina3848@gmail.com
Portfolio
LinkedIn
GitHub

EXPERIENCE

HOWMIES, Nigeria — Full Stack Engineer

June 2020 - Present

HOWMIES is a start-up to provide affordable and easy-to-access housing services.

- Worked with five engineers in building a property listing system (similar to Airbnb).
- Implemented new functionalities and data structuring to improve performance by reducing query time for Web API backend using Typescript, Express.js, and JWT for user authentication.
- Used Netlify and Render for hosting.
- Integrated with Nodemailer for email and SMS notifications.
- Write efficient unit and integration tests.
- Set up automated testing with Git actions (CI/CD).
- Reviewed code and Improved structure.
- Document API.



Euidem I.T Solutions, Lagos, Nigeria — Backend Engineer

https://www.linkedin.com/company/euidem-i.t-solutions

August 2021 - December 2022

Euidem I.T Solutions is a company that offers design and build services from initial idea to final execution.

- Partnered with product managers, stakeholders, and designers to build new product offerings and tooling across the platform.
- Worked with the backend team, focused on building APIs for a product suggestion service.
- Developed frontend application using Typescript, React.js, Redux, Material.
- Developed Web APIs for different projects with Node.js, Typescript, Express, Nest, MongoDB, SQL.
- Refactored 40% of legacy code to make the codebase cleaner and

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

TypeScript

Node.js

Nest.js

React.js

Next.js

DATABASES

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

MySQL

SKILLS

Research

High emotional intelligence

Empathy

Optimism

Effective communication

Problem-solving

Critical thinking

Collaboration

Agile Processes

TOOLS

Git/GitHub/Gitlab

GitHub Actons/ Gitlab CI

Kubernetics

Postman

improved performance using newer React functionalities.

- Improved customer experience by implementing scheduling service appointments (pick up and drop offs)
- Improved analytics by tracking suggestion history
- Write efficient unit and integration tests.
- Review code.
- Properly document APIs.



Docker

TESTS

Jest

CLOUD SERVICES

AWS

Heroku

Digital Ocean

Freelance, Nigeria — Full-stack Engineer

From January 2020

- Implemented a real-time chat system with room designs that enable users create groups and a chat to enhance user experience using Nodejs, Express, and Socket.io. .
- Developed REST APIs for a tourist site using Node.js, Express.js, JWT for user authentication and ejs for view engine.
- Integrated with Nodemailer for email and SMS notifications.
- Developed a full-stack e-commerce application with an admin layout using React.js, Redux, Node.js, and Express.js.
- Used MongoDB and PostgreSql for data storage.
- Set up Gitlab automatic code deployment (CI/CD).
- Set up unit testing with Jest.
- JWT for authentication service that handles auth for both the main app and an admin app.
- Stripe for payments.
- Heroku for hosting



LANGUAGES

English - Fluent.

PROJECTS

Some of my project cannot be displayed here due to NDA

Also checkout my **Portfolio** and my **YouTube Channel** for more of my work

Shop@Kego — An e-commerce shopping app.

Shop Kego

Mosocial — A social app with chat.

Mosocial

EDUCATION

Skillup Africa, Lagos —Backend Engineer

From August 2021 - February 2022

Niger Delta University, Wilberforce Island Bayelsa — *B.Eng. Marine Engineering*

From September 2014 - June 2020